Ahmed MAS

Software Engineer with 4 years experience of writing clean code. Specializing in software development using K8s distributed systems, Golang, Python, and GRPC services and end-to-end data pipelines as a result of working in an Al/ML focused spend-to-pay platform

EXPERIENCE

AppZen Inc., Remote — *Software Engineer*

JUNE 2021 - NOVEMBER 2022

- Spearheaded K8s cost optimization saving 3-4k/month using Prometheus, Grafana, and Kubecost
- Developed platform for AI/ML development and deployment using MLFlow, Golang, GRPCs, and Temporal
- Developed and delivered computer vision ML PoCs using Dask, Sklearn, Mlflow, and Elasticsearch
- Developed core end-to-end data pipelines using Golang,
 Temporal, GRPCS, Elasticsearch and SQS

AppZen Inc., Remote — AI/ML Service Engineer

OCTOBER 2020 - JUNE 2021

- Profiled/refactored Python code creating 93% reduction in runtime (150 s -> 10 s)
- Developed shared internal libraries reducing tech debt using Python, Dask, and MLFlow
- Developed RnD PoCs apps using Python and Seldon

AppZen Inc., Arizona — L3 Support Engineer

JANUARY 2019 - OCTOBER 2020

- Developed automation scripts saving 4 hours a week
- Debugged core ML/AI models (Python; Java)
- Tackled backlog of customer feature requests (Python)

EDUCATION

Heriot-Watt University, UAE— (Hons) *BSc: Psych with Management*

SEPTEMBER 2012 - MAY 2016

Graduated with honors (2:1) second class upper distinction | Academic merit scholarship

CONTACT INFORMATION

31 East Duke Drive Tempe, AZ 85283 (480) 265-6659 ahmed.mu.mas@gmail.com

SKILLS

Python | Golang |
Kubernetes | Temporal |
SQL | Elasticsearch |
Protocol Buffers | MLFlow |
Docker | Microservices |
Jenkins | ArgoCD | Seldon |
CI/CD | ML/AI Models |
NoSQL | GRPC | Distributed
Systems

LANGUAGES

English | Arabic

PROJECTS

Stock Option Tracker

Developed an app to analyze stock option data using Yahoo Finance API

Links

LinkedIn:

linkedin.com/in/ahmed-mas

HackerRank:

hackerrank.com/ahmed mas

GitHub:

github.com/Ahmed-Mas